-==www.RagBear.com==- 是, 首相  第1季第1集
本字幕仅供学习交流，严禁用于商业用途
-=破烂熊字幕组=- 翻译:Celeste 校对&时间轴:tpring
大展宏图
(国防部)
(Ministry of Defence)
告诉我 将军 热线在哪里?
Tell me, General. Where's the hotline?
哪一条?      连接俄国的那一条
Which one? The one to Russia.
"红色热线" 先生
The red hotline, sir.
在唐宁街
It's in Downing Street.
紧急情况下我能直接接通苏联主席吗?
I can get through to the Soviet president?
理论上可以
Theoretically, yes.
理论上?     我们是这么跟记者说的
Theoretically? That's what we tell journalists.
确实接通过一次克林姆林宫 那边是个接线员
We once get through to a switchboard operator.
他不能转过去吗?     不知道 他英语不好
Couldn't he put you through? Never found out.
这条线多久测试一次?     尽量少测试
How often is it tested? Not too often.
否则会给另一端带来不必要的恐慌
It creates unnecessary panic at the other end,
考虑到核武器 还是避免恐慌为好
avoid panic where nuclear weapons are concerned.
对哦     就是这个
Yes. Now, this is it.
啊 好
Ah, good.
这是什么?     扳机 首相
What is it? The trigger, Prime Minister.
扳机?     核武器扳机 按钮
The trigger? The nuclear trigger, the button.
这个?     间接地说 是的
This? Indirectly, yes.
这条电报线直通诺伍德海军基地
This is the telex communication with HMS Northwood.
您发一个电码 基地通讯员回一个确认码
You send a coded signal and Northwood sends another signal.
这样他就知道是您了
So he knows it's from you.
一旦您的指令被确认
When the instruction's been authenticated,
基地会下令给一艘北极星潜艇 他们就按按钮
Northwood sends a command to a Polaris submarine.
就这样?     就这样
Just like that? Just like that.
只要我下命令?     只要您下命令
When I say so? When you say so.
不会有人跟我争论吗?
Wouldn't anybody argue with me?
军人的天职是服从 不是提问
Serving officers obey orders without question.
如果我那时喝醉了呢?
What if I were to get drunk?
基本上 您别喝醉比较安全
On the whole, it would be safer if you didn't.
天哪
Blimey!
这是您的工作 是您要干的 首相
It's your job and you wanted it, Prime Minister.
假设我昏了头呢?     内阁会发现的
Supposing I were to go off my rocker? The Cabinet might notice.
我可不指望 说真的 要是我下完令反悔了呢?
I wouldn't count on it. supposing I did and then changed my mind?
没关系 反正也没人会发现了 不是吗?
That's all right. No one would ever know, would they?
我们有多少核弹头?
How many bombs are there?
4艘北极星核潜艇 每艘16颗 各3个弹头
Four Polaris submarines, 16 missiles on each.
总共呢?      192
But how many actual bombs? 192.
每一颗至少比广岛的强大5倍
Each one at least five times the power of the Hiroshima bomb.
我知道您怎么想 "不太多"?
You're thinking, ''Not very many.''
我不知道 似乎足够了
I don't know. That seems enough.
比起1200颗瞄准英国的苏联核弹 不算多
Not with 1200 Soviet missiles trained on Britain
1200?      嗯
1200? Hmm.
反正大不列颠总是以寡击众
Britain's always fought against the odds
西班牙无敌舰队 不列颠之战
the Armada, Battle of Britain.
是的 等我们拥有三叉戟 我们的火力会大大增强
Yes, and we'll have more firepower when we get Trident.
眼下 谢天谢地还有陆军
Thank goodness for conventional forces!
陆军最多能拖住俄国人72小时
They would hold the Russians for at most 72 hours.
就这?      嗯
Is that all? Hmm.
所以如果有紧急情况发生
So in an emergency
我就得当机立断作出决定?
I would have to make an instant decision?
不 您至少有12小时      12小时?
No, you'd probably have 12 hours. 12 hours?
我们不应该改善这个情况吗?
Shouldn't we do something about this?
是 但20年以来 政客们总说他们养不起陆军
politicians have said they can't afford the conventional forces.
陆军太贵了 首相
Conventional forces are very expensive, Prime Minister.
按一下按钮便宜很多很多
Much cheaper just to press a button.
那么这次会议您觉得多长时间为好?
So how long should we allow for this meeting?
72小时...      好的
72 hours... Fine.
只是新西兰专员而已
It's only the New Zealand High Commissioner.
72小时是不是太慷慨了点?
Isn't 72 hours a bit generous?
我只是在想我们能抵挡俄国人多长时间
I was just thinking how long we could hold the Russians.
如果我们能说服美国人加强他们的陆军...
If we persuaded the Americans to strengthen THEIR forces...
我觉得这样不会有什么改变
I don't think it'll make much difference.
在德国的美国军队都磕药
The American troops in Germany are all so drug-ridden,
他们也不知道自己是哪一边的
they don't know which side they're on anyway.
上次北约演习的时候
And during the last NATO exercises,
美国大兵在树林里解散
the U.S. troops dispersed
然后和女性士兵一起去了树林里野餐
and picnicked in the woods with lady soldiers.
那么其他的北约军队呢?
What about the other NATO armies?
他们很好 至少在工作日的时候
They're all right. On weekdays, anyway.
工作日?
Weekdays?
对 荷兰 丹麦 比利时军队周末要回家的
The Dutch, Danish and Belgian armies go home for the weekend.
所以 假定俄国人真要侵略
So if the Russians are to invade
我们希望他们在周一至周五间侵略?
we'd prefer them to do it between Mondays and Fridays?
很多人知道这件事吗?
Is this widely known?
既然我都知道了 俄国人肯定知道
If I know it, I'm sure the Russians do.
克林姆林宫得到北约消息的速度
The Kremlin usually gets NATO information
通常比我们唐宁街10号快
before it filters through to Number 10.
所以我们得依赖三叉戟?      等它送来
So it comes back to Trident? When it comes.
如果它能用      如果它能...
If it works. If it wor...
你说什么?      通常新来的武器
What do you mean? Normally, when new weapons are delivered,
弹头都无法配合火箭架
the warheads don't fit the ends of the rockets.
北极星就是这样 您知道的
That's what happened to Polaris. You know the sort of thing
电线不行啦 芯片出错啦
wiring faults, microchip failure.
有好几年我们都无法正常发射北极星
We couldn't fire Polaris for some years.
巡航导弹可能也是 还有三叉戟
Cruise is probably the same. Trident might be too.
这简直不能容忍 我们该把制造商送上法庭
We should take the manufacturers to court.
我们不能冒被媒体发现的险
We can't risk the publicity
国家安全 他们是知道的
security and they know it!
那就不能换一个制造商?
We should change the manufacturers.
我们总在换的
We do all the time.
制造商也明白 这就是为什么
The manufacturers know that too. That's why
一枚鱼雷击中了高尔夫球场
that torpedo landed on Sandwich golf course.
高尔夫球场?我没在报纸上看到
Sandwich golf course? I didn't read that in the papers.
当然不会 政府掩盖了消息
Of course not. There was a cover-up.
只是第二天早上球员们
The members just found a new bunker
发现第七道旁边多了条沟
on the 7th fairway the next morning.
所以鱼雷都不能正常工作?
So the torpedoes don't work either?
不 只是新的 其他的都可以
No, only the new ones. The others are fine.
二战时候设计出来的的那些
The ones designed during the Second World War.
40年前的?      对 它们久经测试
Over 40 years ago? They had lots of testing.
现代武器很难做完这些测试      为什么?
You can't afford that with the modern ones. Why not?
如果爆发核战 首相 时间不会久到
Well, if there's a nuclear war, it won't last long enough
能让武器测试完为止
for the weapons to be tested.
关于国防还有什么事情我得知道的?
Are there other things I don't know about the UK's defence?
我不知道 首相 我不知道你不知道什么
I don't know, Prime Minister. I don't know what you don't know.
不过如果您需要不同意见 我知道
The government's chief scientific adviser
政府首席科学顾问和国防部的看法不太一样
sees the problem differently from the MoD.
我现在就想见他
I'd like to see him now.
晚一点邀请他来喝杯酒比较明智
A late drink might be wiser.
最好别让内阁办公室知道
Better not to let the Cabinet Office know.
汉弗莱爵士会不高兴的
Sir Humphrey gets upset.
他不认为那位顾问属于我们的人
He doesn't regard him as one of us.
我记得他在阿荷姆得过优秀军人勋章
I thought he won the DSO at Arnhem.
这也不能弥补他古怪的奥地利口音
That doesn't make up for speaking with an Austrian accent.
他没进过牛津剑桥 甚至伦敦政经学院
He didn't go to Oxford or Cambridge even go to the LSE.
首相 您相信核武防御吗?
Prime Minister, you believe in the nuclear deterrent?
哦 是的      为什么?
Oh, yes. Why?
什么?      为什么?
Pardon? Why?
因为它能防御
Because it deters.
谁?      什么?
Whom? Pardon?
谁?它防御谁?      防御俄国入侵
Whom? Whom does it deter? The Russians from attacking us.
为什么?      什么?
Why? Pardon?
什么?
Why?
他们知道 如果他们侵略我就按按钮
They know if they launched an attack, I'd press the button.
你会吗?      为什么不会?
You would? Well, wouldn't I?
你会吗?
Well, would you?
最后关头 我当然会
At the last resort, yes, I certainly would.
我想我当然会的 当然
Well, I think I certainly would. Yes.
几时才算最后关头呢?
And what is the last resort?
如果俄国侵略西欧的话
If the Russians invaded western Europe.
可你只有12小时 所以
You only have 12 hours to decide, so you're saying
你的最后关头就是最初反应?
the last resort is the first response?
是吗?
Am I?
不用担心 俄国怎么会想要整个欧洲?
Why should the Russians annex the whole of Europe?
他们连阿富汗都控制不了
They can't even control Afghanistan.
不 如果他们尝试侵略 会用"香肠战术"
No, if they try anything, it will be salami tactics.
香肠?      一片接一片
Salami tactics? Slice by slice.
每次一小片儿
One small piece at a time.
当他们侵略西柏林的时候你会按下按钮吗?
So will you press the button if they invade West Berlin?
看情况      什么情况?
It all depends. On what?
好吧 第一步
Scenario one.
西柏林暴动
Riots in West Berlin,
建筑物在燃烧
buildings in flames.
东柏林消防队跨界前来救援 你按吗?
East German fire brigade crosses the border. Would you press?
东柏林警察也过来了 按吗?
The East German police come with them. The button...?
然后是军队 更多的军队 他们说是来控制骚乱的
Then some troops, more troops just for riot control, they say.
再然后 俄国军队代替了东德 按吗?
East German troops are replaced by Russian troops. Button?
俄国军队不肯走了
Then the Russian troops don't go.
他们受邀留下援助民政部门
They are invited to stay to support civilian administration.
民政部门关闭了道路和机场
The civilian administration closes roads and Tempelhof Airport.
现在要按吗?       我需要时间考虑
Now you press the button? I need time to think about it.
你有12小时      是吗?
You have 12 hours. Have I?
这只是你虚构的      您是今时的首相
You're inventing this. You are Prime Minister today.
北约总部随时会来电话
The phone might ring now from NATO HQ.
喂? 北约总部 首相
Hello...? Yes. NATO HQ, Prime Minister.
您能参加四月的年会吗?
Can you address their annual conference in April?
我以为可以的 现在我不大确定了
I thought I could. I'm not so sure now.
是
Yes.
第二步
Scenario two.
俄国军队故意跨越了西德的国界
The Russian army cross the West German frontier.
这是最后关头吗?      不是
Is that the last resort? No.
好吧 第三步
Right, scenario three.
假设俄国侵占了西德 比利时 荷兰 法国?
Suppose they invaded West Germany, Belgium, Holland, France?
坦克到了英吉利海峡 整装待发了呢?
their troops have reached the Channel and are poised to invade?
最后关头?      不
Is that the last resort? No.
为什么?
Why not?
我们参与核战的原因是保护自己
We'd only fight a nuclear war to defend ourselves.
怎能用自杀保护自己?
That would be committing suicide!
那什么才是最后关头 皮卡迪利(伦敦商业街)?
So what is the last resort? Piccadilly?
沃特福峡谷维修站?
Watford Gap service station?
革命剧院?
The Reform Club?
也许核武防御根本没意义       它有
Maybe the nuclear deterrent makes no sense. Yes, it does.
如果俄国或者美国有核弹 另一边必须也有
If the Russians or Americans have the bomb, so must the other
留着北极星 以防万一      你的建议呢?
And keep Polaris just in case. What are you proposing?
取消三叉戟订单 省下五十五亿 花在陆军上
Spend the ?5 billion you save on conventional forces.
反正你又不会按那个按钮
You wouldn't really press the button.
如果别无选择 我会的
I might if I had no choice.
不会把你逼到别无选择 他们会用香肠战术
They'll never put you in a situation where you have no choice.
假设我们取消三叉戟 把55亿花在陆军上
Supposing we cancel Trident and support conventional forces?
我们要买什么 坦克?      不 要买ET
What do we spend it on? Tanks? No, we spend it on E.T.
外星人?
Extra-terrestrials?
紧急应对技术
Emergent technology.
那是什么?      智能弹头
What's that? Smart missiles
瞄准系统 红外线
target finding, infrared.
谁来操纵ET呢?      一支庞大的陆军军队
Who would operate this E.T? A large conventional army.
一支庞大的陆……
A large convention...
我有个主意
I've got an idea.
等等
Wait a minute!
我觉得这个计划很可行 第一 取消三叉戟
I think I can see how to do this. First, we cancel Trident.
对      也不再买巡航导弹了
Yes. We don't buy Cruise either.
对      然后恢复征兵制
Yes. Then we introduce conscription.
对
Yes.
不仅解决了国防 还能解决就业问题
Not only solve defence problems but unemployment as well.
首相 征兵会不会太有魄力?
Isn't conscription a courageous policy?
魄力? 老天 会吗?
Courageous? Oh, my God, is it?
不会不会 全额就业率的时候才会
No, no. In times of full employment, it would be.
可现在我们只是
But now we'd just give
给失业的年轻人找点事干
unemployed young people something to do.
教他们各种技巧 甚至可能教会他们认字
teach them trades and skills. even teach them to read.
文盲不能退伍 还能教他们讲点卫生
The army never discharged anyone who was illiterate.
给年轻人全面教育 去弥补他们的素质教育
comprehensive education make up for comprehensive education
就叫它"国民服务"把年轻人都送去社会服务
Call it national service. Send them into the community services
同一个政策 可以解决
With one policy, we solve our
国防 教育 就业问题 对吧教授?
defence, educational and unemployment problems.
这真美妙 我可以预见
This is wonderful. I see it all now.
"大不列颠的新未来 哈克的宏伟蓝图"
''A new deal for Britain Hacker's Grand Design.''
有时 在我们伟大岛国
From time to time in our great island story,
责任会降临于一人...
it falls to one man...
领导人民走出阴影渊谷
to lead his people out of the valley of the shadow
走向和平与繁荣之阳光高原
and into the sunlit uplands of peace and prosperity.
为什么我以前就没想到呢?
Why didn't I think of this before?
因为我们刚见面啊
Because we only just met.
你好 亲爱的
Hello, darling!
午餐吃什么?      你说呢
What's for lunch? You tell me.
你要出去吗?      社工大会 我告诉过你了
Are you going somewhere? Voluntary services committee.
噢 对 我想吃点炒蛋什么的
of course. I just thought a few scrambled eggs or something.
我记得冰箱里还有些鸡蛋
I think there's some eggs in the fridge.
我自己炒?      我们说好的 我继续工作
You want me to do it? We agreed that I'd carry on with my work.
当然      外交部电报 首相
Yes, of course. Foreign Office telegrams, Prime Minister.
放一边吧      再说
Put them over there. It's bad enough
住这个金鱼缸里已经够烦了
living in this goldfish bowl.
每次我出门 都要挤过一打记者 50个游客
I have to walk past a dozen journalists and 50 tourists!
一点隐私都没有      没这回事
There's no privacy anywhere. That's not true.
抱歉 阁下 安全检查 我能四处看看吗?
Sorry, Prime Minister. Security check. Can I just look around?
可以 请吧      隐私?
Yes, carry on. Privacy?
你可以去花园散步嘛
You can always walk in the garden.
被60个人从窗户里盯着看?
With about 60 people staring at you!
像在监狱里放风一样 我们还得
It's like exercising in a prison yard. And we
给这鬼地方付房租 他们应该付我们钱
pay rent for this place. They should pay US!
至少挺安静的
At least it's quiet.
平常很安静的      今早七点半就开始吵了
Usually. That's been going on since half past seven!
他们总得练习吧?      为什么非要在这里?
They've got to practise somewhere. Why here?
他们是皇家骑警啊
That's the Horse Guards' Parade.
检查完毕 阁下 打扰了
All clear, Prime Minister.
安妮 你得明白 人民公仆需要牺牲很多东西的
Annie, a career in public service involves some sacrifice.
好啊 你牺牲你的午餐吧 我快迟到了
Fine, you sacrifice your lunch. I'm late.
可我饿了      噢
I'm hungry! Aw!
你中午吃了什么?      半块巧克力
What did you have for YOUR lunch? Half a Yorkie bar.
另外那半块呢?
Where's the other half?
啊 伯纳
Ah, Bernard!
首相      午餐吃得好吗?
Yes, Prime Minister. Had a good lunch?
还不错 谢谢 首相      在哪吃的?
Oh, quite good. Where did you have it?
内阁餐厅      三道菜?
In the Cabinet mess. Three courses?
是的
Er, yes.
喝了酒?      一杯红酒 是的
Wine? A glass of claret, yes.
想知道我午餐吃了什么吗?
Would you like to know what I had for my lunch?
您想告诉我吗 首相?      什么都没吃
Do you want to tell me, Prime Minister? Nothing!
您在节食?
Are you dieting?
好像这里可以给你和其他秘书提供膳食
It seems there are facilities for feeding allsecretaries,
整个内阁 新闻部 打字小姐 信差
the Cabinet Office, the Press Office, the messengers
就是没有我的 我还住在这里
but not for me and I live here!
抱歉 您太太不能做饭吗?      她要工作
Can't Mrs Hacker cook for you? She's out at work.
我们可以帮您找个厨子      谁付钱?
We'll get you a cook. Who'll pay for it?
您 是您的厨子      多少?
You will. How much?
年薪八千到一万镑      太贵了 我付不起
8,000 to 10,000 a year. I can't afford that!
您可以跟内阁秘书沟通一下      叫他来
Talk to the Cabinet Secretary. Bring him here now.
他就快来了 现在能不能讨论国家大事了?
Shall we press on with the affairs of the nation?
去他的国家大事 我想要个厨子
Stuff the affairs of the nation. I want a cook!
我会帮您找的 同时
I'll look into it.
新闻部的马尔康华伦想跟您谈谈
Malcolm Warren from the Press Office would like a word.
好吧 让他进来
OK, bring him in.
下午好 首相      下午好 马尔康
Good afternoon, Prime Minister. Good afternoon, Malcolm.
内阁秘书要来了 你能说得简洁点吗?
Could we keep this brief?
好的 两件事 第一件最重要
Yes, two things. First, we'll discuss
您的首次首相电视演讲
your first appearance on TV as Prime Minister.
确实重要 得等时间充足的时候
Perhaps we ought to leave it until we've time
深入讨论 第二呢?
to do it thoroughly. What's the other thing?
您对华盛顿的正式访问 次要的      如何?
Your official visit to Washington. What about it?
很多媒体想跟去      让他们跟去
A lot of press want to come. Let them.
很昂贵的      马尔康
It'll be very expensive. Malcolm!
我会在白宫门前 和美国总统肩靠肩地站在一起
I stand on the White House lawn with the President of the USA.
国歌奏响 两位大国领导人站在一起
National anthems, two world leaders together.
显示我们两国之间深厚的友谊与感情
We will tell the world about our happy relationship,
我们的团结 决心
our unity, resolve,
也许聊几句关于我的勇气 智慧 政治才能
a few words perhaps about my own courage, statesmanship.
你难道不明白这对我有多重要
Can't you realise how important this is to me?
不是对我 是对英国
Well, not to me, to Britain.
我们在世界上的地位 我在历史上的地位
Our place in the world, my place in the history books.
是 首相      进来坐 汉弗莱 谢谢 马尔康
Yes, Prime Minister. Come in, Humphrey. Thank you, Malcolm.
马尔康      汉弗莱
Malcolm... Humphrey!
我在思考      很好
I've been thinking... Good.
我做首相有...让我想想 三天了
I've been Prime Minister for, let me see, three days now.
而且是一位很好的首相
And a very good PM you are, too!
我不是让你拍我马屁 虽然确实很顺利
I'm not fishing for compliments, though it has been going well.
哦 当然
Oh, indeed.
能报答老朋友真愉快
It's nice to be able to reward one's old allies.
罗恩琼斯对他的授勋满意吗?
Was Ron Jones pleased with his peerage?
是的 首相 他说他的会员会很高兴
Yes, Prime Minister. He said his members would be delighted.
会员?      工会会员 国家联合...
His members? Of his union. The National Federation...
不是他 我说的是我们的后座议员
I didn't mean him. I meant our backbencher!
我说给罗恩琼斯授勋 不是那个罗恩琼斯
I meant to give a peerage to Ron Jones, not Ron Jones!
真活见鬼了
Bloody hell!
如果这能安慰您的话 我想他非常高兴
If it's any consolation, he was awfully pleased.
他当然了 罗恩琼斯怎么办 也给他授个勋?
I bet he was! What are we going to do about Ron Jones's peerage?
恕我直言 首相 我们不能一下
Prime Minister, we can't send
往上议院塞两个罗恩琼斯爵士
two Lord Ron Jones to the upper house.
看起来像搞批发的
It'll look like a job lot.
我们得给他点什么      他喜欢什么 看电视?
I've got to give him something. Does he watch television?
他根本没电视       好极了 给他BBC吧
He hasn't even got a set. Fine. Make him a governor of the BBC.
还有什么?      还有件小事
Anything else? Yes, one small thing.
我需要一个厨子兼管家
I need a cook/housekeeper for the flat.
您可以登广告
You can advertise.
不 公派的厨子兼管家       这有点困难
No, a government cook/housekeeper. That could be difficult.
为什么?       这是您的私宅
Why? It's a private home.
只不过碰巧是政府办公处
Happen to be in a goverment building
我得住在这 在这吃饭
I happen to be live and eat here
我只想找个人做饭 不是没道理
I just want somebody to cook my lunch. It's not unreasonable.
不 只是不可能
No, it's just not possible.
我有权炸掉全世界 却不能要一盘炒蛋?
I can blow up the world, but not ask for scrambled eggs?
您有权力申请      如果我请德国大使吃饭呢?
You can ASK for them. What if I asked the German ambassador?
这是可以的正式预约 官方招待
That's OK official engagement, government hospitality.
我们很高兴提供七道菜的大餐
We'll provide a seven-course meal
葡萄酒和白兰地 没问题
with wine and brandy.
德国大使的午餐就是政府活动 我的就不是?
The Germans lunch is government business, but mine isn't?
不止德国 对任何大使都是
That is so. Any ambassador's.
好 伯纳 拿我的行程表
Fine. Bernard, get the diary
星期一请德国大使吃午餐
On Monday, I'll have lunch with the German ambassador.
星期二 法国大使 星期三 美国大使
On Tuesday, with the French; Wednesday, with the American
别忘了英联邦 星期四 新西兰专员
on Thursday, with the New Zealand High Commissioner.
联合国有多少个国家?      158
How many countries in the UN? 158.
这能吃六个月了 然后就从头再吃一轮
That'll take up six months, then we'll start round again.
您不能每天都跟大使吃午饭的
You can't have lunch with ambassadors every day
有时候有别的公务宴会
There will be other official lunches.
那更好 可以填补空缺
Even better. We'll fill up the odd gaps.
外交部也许不会同意      怎么
The Foreign Office might have some views on that.
他们说首相跟大使吃一次午餐
They say that one Prime Minister's lunch with an ambassador
破坏两年的外交成果
destroys two years of patient diplomacy.
我不确定他们怎么看待158次午餐
I'm not quite sure how they'd react to 158.
太荒唐了 难道没人给我做饭吗?
It's absurd that no one caters for us here.
这规矩流传250年了
It's been like that for 250 years.
这是最终定论吗?      250年以来 是的
That's the clinching argument? For 250 years, yes.
抱歉 汉弗莱爵士 没有250年来的定论
It can't have been the clinching argument for 250 years.
因为50年前 只能说200年以来
50 years ago, it had been the clinching argument for 200 years
100年前...
and 100 years ago...
抱歉
Sorry.
汉弗莱 我不信这邪 我要一个厨子兼管家
Humphrey, I want a cook/housekeeper
而且我要你找人给她付薪水
and I want you to see that she's paid for.
好吧 让我换个方式说
Well, let me put it like this.
您想要媒体宣布 您当首相以来第一个举措
Do you want the press to announce that your first act
就是给您自己每年加薪1万磅?
was to give yourself a salary increase of ?,000 to ?0,000?
不告诉他们就成了
We wouldn't tell them.
我们别无选择 首相的收支必须要公开
Prime Ministers' expenses must be published.
难道不能隐瞒?      透明政府 信息自由
There's no way that we can't not tell them? Open government.
我们必须开诚布公地告诉媒体
We should always tell the press freely and frankly anything
一切他们自有办法查到的事
that they could easily find out some other way.
一定有办法      250年以来都没有
There must be some solution. There hasn't been for 250 years.
现在能讨论国家大事了吗? 您刚才说您在考虑
Now may we discuss government business?
啊 是的 刚说到我的领导是非常成功的
We're agreed that my premiership has been a great success.
哦 当然
Oh, indeed.
对 我在考虑如何让成功延续下去
what can I do to continue this run of success?
您考虑过"无为"吗?
Have you considered masterly inactivity?
不 汉弗莱 首相必须强硬
No, Humphrey, a Prime Minister must be firm.
当然 那么强硬的无为呢?
Indeed. How about firm masterly inactivity?
不 我要强硬
No, I shall be firm.
我决定取消三叉戟订单 把55亿花到陆军上去
I'll cancel Trident, channel ?5 billion into conventional forces
而且扩大征兵
and reintroduce conscription.
同一个政策 我们可以解决国防 财政平衡
At one stroke, we shall solve our defence, balance of payments,
就业率 教育问题
unemployment and educational problems all at once.
你觉得呢 汉弗莱?
What do you say, Humphrey?
您不能把整个国防部署彻底洗牌啊
You can't reorganise the entire defence of the realm just like that.
我是首相 我有这个权力
I'm the Prime Minister. I have the power.
对 遵循法律和宪法 行政管理的前例
Yes, within the law and the constitution and the precedent,
可行性预算和内阁政府
budgetary feasibility and cabinet government.
您要改买巡航导弹?      不 不再买核武器了
You'll buy Cruise instead? No, no more nuclear weapons.
可首相....您不是秘密的片面限武派吧?
But, Prime Minister... You're not a secret unilateralist?
不是 我们还有北极星呢
No, we still have Polaris.
北极星都老掉牙了
Polaris is a ramshackle old system.
苏联很容易发明个飞弹拦截北极星
The Soviets might develop a ballistic missile defence system
什么时候?      战略角度来说 任何时候
By when? In strategic terms, any day now.
精确一点说 几几年?
By what year precisely?
2020? 但这比你想象要快
2020? But that's sooner than you think!
你是说核武防御能拦截192个北极星吗?
Are you saying that this system would stop all Polaris missiles?
也不是全部 事实上 97%
Not all, virtually all 97%.
有5个炸弹会通过咯?
That would leave five bombs that would get through?
只是5个而已
A mere five!
分别去莫斯科 列宁格勒和明斯克
Obliterating Moscow, Leningrad and Minsk.
是的 但这就是全部了
Yes, but that's about all.
够吓唬俄国人了
Enough to make the Russians stop and think.
但这不公平 有了三叉戟
But it's not fair. With Trident
我们可以扫除整个东欧
we could obliterate the whole of eastern Europe
可我不想扫除东欧      这是个威慑
I don't want to! It's a deterrent.
这是唬人 我大概根本不会用
It's a bluff. I probably wouldn't use it.
可他们不知道您大概不用
They don't know you probably wouldn't.
他们大概知道      对 大概
They probably do. Yes, probably,
但他们不能肯定您真的不用
but they can't certainly know.
他们大概真的知道
They probably certainly know.
对 就算他们可能真的知道您不用
though they probably certainly know that you probably wouldn't,
也不确定 尽管您可能不用
they don't certainly know that although you probably wouldn't,
您就肯定没有可能用
there's no probability that you certainly would!
啥?
What?
归根结底 这是个简单的问题
It all boils down to one simple issue.
您是首相 您不认为英国该拥有最好的吗?
You are the PM. Shouldn't Great Britain have the best?
那当然了      很好
Yes, of course.
如果您走进核武展览会 您就会买三叉戟
If you walked into a showroom, you would buy Trident!
它那么可爱 优雅 美丽
It's lovely, it's elegant, it's beautiful.
它显然是最好的 而英国应该拥有最好的
It is quite simply the best, and Britain should have the best.
在核武世界中 它是萨维罗西装
In the world of the nuclear missile, it is the Savile Row suit,
劳斯莱斯轿车
the Rolls-Royce Corniche,
1945年的拉菲红酒
the Ch鈚eau Lafite 1945.
是哈罗德(伦敦豪华商场)会卖的导弹
It is the nuclear missile Harrods would sell you.
我还用多说吗?
What more can I say?
除了它要花55亿 我们根本用不上
That it costs ?5 billion and we don't need it.
哈罗德卖的东西不都这样
You can say that about anything at Harrods.
将军 我正想和您谈谈
Ah, General! I was hoping to have a word with you.
我想问您些事情 您不一定爱听
I wanted to sound you out about something. You'll not like it.
尽管说 首相
Tell me the worst.
军方可能不大欢迎 那也没辙
It will be very unpopular with the services.
我计划取消三叉戟      好主意
I'm planning to cancel Trident. Good idea.
别忙 别太快下结论 先别争论...
don't jump in too quickly. No good trying to argue...
你刚才说什么?      好主意
What did you say? It's a good idea.
你同意 为什么?      当然
You're in favour? Why?
我们根本不需要 完全是浪费钱
We don't need it. Complete waste of money.
和我说的一样      您说得对
That's what I said. You're right.
国防部都同意吗?      海军想保留
The whole defence staff agree? The navy want to keep it.
要放在他们潜艇上
On their ships.
拿走三叉戟 他们就没什么重要性了
Take away Trident and they'd hardly have a role left.
空军呢?       您可以问他们
And the RAF? You could ask them.
如果您想知道车间机械师的想法
If you're interested in the opinion of garage mechanics
他们希望保留
They'd want to keep it.
他们想驾驶飞机从空中丢炸弹
They want to drop the bomb from an aeroplane.
他们就喜欢从空中往下丢东西 但又丢不准
They just like dropping things on people, no good at it.
甚至无法接近史丹利港口跑道
Couldn't even close the runway at Port Stanley.
也许永远找不到莫斯科
Probably never find Moscow,
就算找到了 也打不中
and if they did they'd miss it.
如果军方喜欢 怎么才能让这政策通过呢?
How do we get the policy through if only the army is in favour?
您知道 国防部人事处长职位快出缺了
As you know, the Chief of Defence Staff job is becoming vacant.
理论上该轮到海军了 但这是您的决定
Technically, it's the navy's turn, but it's your decision.
只要您高兴 可以任命任何士兵
If you appoint a soldier, it's up to you.
将军 您不正是最资深的士兵吗?
General, aren't you the most senior soldier?
碰巧 我也这么想
As it happens, I believe I am.
谢谢 很好的建议
Thank you. Good advice.
首相 这是格拉索夫人
Prime Minister, this is Mrs Glossop.
太神奇了      怎么了?
Extraordinary thing! What?
总算发现一位有点理智的首相了
I've come across a Prime Minister with a bit of sense.
是吗 哪里的? 哪个幸运的国家?
Really? Where? Which is the lucky country?
我们的 他想取消三叉戟
Ours. He's cancelling Trident.
我简直不相信我的耳朵
I could hardly believe my ears.
真惊讶你居然会喜欢恢复征兵
I'm surprised you're happy about reintroducing conscription.
征兵? 他没提征兵
He didn't say anything about conscription.
正是如此 降低失业率 捞选票
Slashes unemployment, wins votes.
征兵? 我们是世界级精锐部队
We're an elite army, best in the world.
专业 勇敢 有纪律
Professional, tough, disciplined.
我们可不要一堆小流氓
We can't bring in a mob of punks
怪胎 瘾君子 神经病
and freaks and junkies and riff-raff.
25万足球流氓?
A quarter of a million football hooligans?
在陆军基地削土豆皮?
Peeling potatoes in Aldershot?
就知道你会这么说
I thought you'd say that.
会成为普通军队的
It'll be just an ordinary army.
就像赢了二战那一支?
Like the one that won the last war?
平等机会纯属胡闹 像美国一样
All this equal opportunity nonsense, like America!
士兵到达之前 他们都不知道是男是女
They don't know if the troops posted to them are men or women
有时候到了也不知道      对
Sometimes not even then. Quite!
保留三叉戟要好得多
Much better to keep Trident.
就知道你会这么说
I thought you'd say that.
我们得阻止他 你去阻止他
You must stop him.
没法就这样阻止首相
One can't just stop the Prime Minister.
我们要做什么?      让他降降速
What do we do? We must slow him down.
反正一两个月后
After a few months, most new Prime Ministers
大多数首相动力都会少一半
have more or less ground to a halt anyway.
所以 明早我和美国大使谈谈
I'll have a word with the American ambassador tomorrow morning.
好主意      就知道你会这么说
Good idea. I thought you'd say that.
哦 你好
Oh, hello!
新闻部要保证BBC和ITN
I want to make sure that the BBC and ITN
都在白宫草地上占有利地形
get good coverage on the White House lawn.
拍我和总统的特写      好
Shot of me and the President
还有白宫内部 就我和总统两个人
Then there'll be more photo coverage inside the White House.
很好
Splendid.
还要拍我和总统
Then there'll be coverage of
第二天会谈开始的情形      好
me and the President at the start of talks the next day.
然后是总统对我说再见的时候
Then the President will say goodbye to me.
我希望他能用左手扶着我的手肘
I hope he takes my elbow with his left hand.
就像对德国总理那样      德国总理
He did that with the West German Chancellor.
能不能跟大使馆说说 预定这个动作?
Any chance of ensuring that beforehand with the embassy?
可能很困难 您能看看内阁议程吗?
That could be difficult. Could you look at the Cabinet agenda?
我真不知道我们设立个大使馆作甚
I don't know what we have embassies for.
每次你要求他们做点重要的事
Any time you ask them to do something really important
对英国重要的
important for Britain...
我们不是要讨论取消三叉戟吗?
Weren't we to discuss scrapping Trident?
当然要讨论 首相
Indeed we were, Prime Minister.
但我认为您该首先
But I thought in the first instance you might
周详考虑一下才明智
think it wiser to go into it thoroughly,
讨论各种潜在可能性 这可是帝国的国防
as we are discussing the defence of the realm.
你想阻止我 汉弗莱
You're trying to stop me, Humphrey.
不 首相 但内阁必须周详考虑
No, but the Cabinet must have all the facts.
这倒新鲜
That's a novel idea.
有个特殊理由 我认为您可能想要暂缓
There is a reason why I thought you might leave it for a while.
什么      美国大使私下告诉我
I've learned from the American ambassador informally
他们会非常不悦
that they would be very upset
如果取消三叉戟订单
if we were to cancel Trident
并不再从他们那里购买任何核武
and not order another of their missiles instead.
我可以和总统当面商讨这件麻烦事
I might as well have it out with the President.
问题就在这里 首相
That's the point.
您与总统会面的议程必须事先议定
The agenda of your meeting must be agreed in advance.
您不能飘洋过海 跑那里去东扯西拉
You can't just go over there for a chat.
为什么不?      呃 您...
Why not? Well, you...
您也许会找不到话说
You might not think of anything to say.
如果您非要向美国人提这个 计划会改变
If this proposal were put to them there will be a change of plan.
什么改变?
What change of plan?
您将不会与总统会面
Your meeting would not be with the President.
改由副总统接待      副总统?
You'd be entertained by the Vice-President. The Vice-President?!
副总统? 你开玩笑吧       恐怕是的 首相
You can't be serious! I'm afraid so, Prime Minister.
连博茨瓦纳总理都见到总统了
Even Botswana was met by the President.
我在新闻上看见了
I saw it on the news.
博茨瓦纳没有取消三叉戟订单
Botswana hadn't just cancelled an order for Trident.
他们肯定会解释说 总统得了结膜炎
I'm sure they'll explain that the President had catarrh
或伤了大拇指什么的
or bruised his thumb or something.
或者是睡过头了
Fallen asleep perhaps.
这次会晤是至关重要的公关事件
This meeting with the President is vital for PR.
所以您应该暂缓三叉戟的事
Then you should postpone the Trident discussion.
汉弗莱 首相必须显示 唐宁街10号里
A Prime Minister must show that there is
有新的思维和强硬的双手
a new mind and a firm hand at Number 10.
他必须显得有所作为
He must be seen to have made his mark.
但是您有啊 首相      什么?
But you have, Prime Minister. How?
一个厨子 从内阁餐厅里出?
A cook... seconded from the Cabinet Office canteen?
在这里的公寓给我做午餐?
To cook lunch for me here at the flat?
您所有前任首相都没做到的事
Something that none of your predecessors ever accomplished.
史书中的位置      就说嘛
A place in the history books.I say!
让他们看看谁说话算数 是吗?
We've shown them who's in charge, haven't we?
的确 首相
Indeed we have, Prime Minister.
新思想 强硬的双手和三叉戟
A new mind and a firm hand and Trident.
史书中的位置啊
A place in the history books, you say.
哦 暂时取消三叉戟的内阁议程
Oh, leave Trident off the Cabinet agenda for the time being
这是我强硬的决定 好吗?
That is my firm decision. All right?
是 首相
Yes, Prime Minister.
破烂熊字幕组 -==www.RagBear.com==- 欢迎加入